前情提要
我把尸體燒了
I burnt the body.
骨頭分開埋的  沒人找得到
Bones are buried separate. No-one will find 'em.
亨利可能和一些極端分子有關系
Henry may have been involved with extremists
并參加了他們的集訓營
and made his way to one of their training camps.
西蒙是不死先知的十二門徒之一
Simon is one of the 12 disciples of the Undead Prophet.
維生黨搜集的情報表明有些團體
Victus has been gathering intelligence on groups
打算帶來二次復生
looking to bring about another Rising.
他們認為
They believe they need
需要先找到第一個復生的人
to find the First Risen before it can start.
不管第一個復生的是誰
Whoever this First Risen is,
我們必須在其他人之前找到他
we want to find them before anyone else does.
我不想跟你待在這里
I don't like being here with you,
我想和朋友們一起
I'd rather be with my friends.
你得找個關心你的好姑娘
You need to find a nice girl who'll take care of you.
愛神依西塔
The Goddess Ishtar.
你還想要完整女友體驗套餐嗎
Are you wanting the full girlfriend experience again?
好啊  寶貝
Hiya, sweetheart.
今天過得怎么樣
How was your day?
艾米是那種需要愛意關懷的人
Amy is someone who needs to see that she's loved.
所以我對她表現出愛意
So I show her love,
因為我確實愛她
because I do love her.
怎么了
Hey, what's the matter?
沒什么  我只是
Nothing, I just...
我一直想要你是不是不好
Is it a bad thing that I want you all the time?
這完全正常
It's perfectly normal.
我一直
I keep...
在想你的雙手
thinking about your hands...
撫摸著我
touching me...
不行  你去部門委員會可不能遲到
No, you mustn't be late for the departmental committee.
他們沒我開始不了
They can't start without me.
那當然
Of course!
老天  菲利普  你真嫻熟
Oh, my God, Philip. You're so adept.
等等
Oh, wait.
請讓我試試
Please, let me try.
我想給你快感
I want to give you pleasure.
教教我吧
Teach me.
好吧
Very well...
菲利普  西維婭來家里了
Philip, we've got a visitor, Sylvia,
你能下來嗎
can you come down?
你說什么  噪音太吵我聽不清
What did you say? I can't hear you with all that noise.
菲利普  菲利普
Philip! Philip?
菲利普  馬上
Philip, now!
第二季  第四集
復生
人人影視英劇社傾情奉獻
翻譯  艾瑞卡 unundu CiciXT
肉松富士
愛卿遛小鳥
木淺薰 小shy
雪莉的苦艾
特別嗚謝  POTO的小飯桶
時間軸
寶寶  Kallen  訥訥
校對  安然若水
后期  寶寶
總監  安然若水
家里只有我管...
Am I the only one in this house...?
我這是干什么
What am I doing?
我給學校打電話
I called them at the school.
說亨利今天不會去學校了
I said, "Henry won't be in today,
他失蹤了
he's gone missing."
你知道他們怎么回答的嗎
D'you know what they said to me?
"謝謝你的來電"  好像無關緊要
"Thank you for your call," Like it were nothing.
菲利普來了
Here's Philip now.
就像是場噩夢  雪莉
It's like a bad dream, Shirley,
一直覺得我一醒
I keep thinking I'll wake up
-他就回來了  -親愛的
- and he'll have come back. - Oh, darling.
我向你保證  蘭思德太太
I assure you, Mrs Lonsdale,
我們已竭盡所能
that everything that can be done...
對不起  瑪克辛·馬丁的話我可不信
I'm sorry, no, that Maxine Martin.
我一眼就能看出誰當著我面在說謊
Well, I can tell when someone's lying to me face.
"亨利跑去參加集訓營了"
"Henry's run off to a training camp."
他才沒去集訓營
He's not in any training camp.
亨利連童子軍都不參加
Henry wouldn't join Cub Scouts,
哪怕隊長是你  菲利普
not even when you were troop leader, Philip.
我跟他說  "跟著隔壁的菲利
I said to him, "Go with Phil from next door,
"他會照顧你的"  "不  我要玩任天堂"
"He'll look after you." "No, playing Nintendo."
他不喜歡集體活動
He's not a joiner.
這兩件事沒必然聯系
The two things aren't necessarily...
我教你怎么用那個吧  菲利普
Let me show you the knack with that, Philip.
一個是童子軍
One is Cub Scouts,
另一個是恐怖分子集訓營
the other's a terrorist training camp.
-告訴她你會幫她  -怎么幫
- Tell her you'll help her. - How?
今天村里不是開大會嗎
Well, your big village meeting's today.
告訴她你會提起這事
Tell her you'll bring it up.
你在教區理事會里面  總歸有點影響力
You're on the parish council, you must have some sway.
影響力  我當然是有
Sway... of course I have.
但我不能本末倒置
I can't upset the order of business.
這次會議極其重要
It's an extremely important meeting.
馬丁女士會指望我...
Ms Martin's going to be looking to me to...
菲利普說他會查查的
Oh, Philip says he'll look into it.
回饋計劃注冊表
你像這樣站在那
You're stood there like that.
我過來  跟你握手
I come in, I shake your hand...
握手
Shake hands.
我受到了驚嚇
I'm alarmed.
你的皮膚冰冷
Your skin is cold to the touch.
不好意思
Sorry about that.
照手冊說
Like in the brochure.
對不起嚇到你了
I'm sorry I caused your anxiety...
西蒙和艾米呢
Where's Simon and Amy?
西蒙有更重要的事要做  他有任務
Simon's got more important things to do, he's got a mission.
還有隱形眼鏡是為了
...and contact lenses on account of...
-減少  -減少人類的緊張情緒
- To minimise. - "To minimise distress caused to living people."
過去二十四小時內我已注射過神經替林
"I've been administered Neurotriptyline in the last 24 hours
不會轉變至狂暴狀態
and will not enter a rabid state."
你一定要說清楚
You have to have it off,
要不然你就是在干什么
otherwise what are you doing?
四處嚇人
Scaring crap out of folk.
你得多練習上上摩絲什么的
You need to work on your mousse application an' all.
均勻用力  一抹到底  對吧
Long, even strokes, yeah?
坐下吧  我給你個六分
Sit down, I'm giving you a six,
這還算是客氣的
and that's being generous.
-下一位  艾米·戴爾  -沒來
- Next, Amy Dyer. - Not here.
西蒙·門羅
Simon Monroe?
耍小聰明是吧
That's very clever, that, innit?
把他們記到不配合名單里
See how clever they are
看看他們還能聰明多久
when they get put on a noncompliants list.
也是給你們所有人一個教訓  別惹麻煩
Lesson there for all of yous, don't take the piss.
集齊所有印章之后呢
What happens when you've got all the stamps?
那你就有所有印章了啊
Well, then, you've got all the stamps.
集滿五張就能去旅行
Get all five sheets and there's an away day...
海濱之旅
to the seaside.
還有你  記得抹摩絲
And you, get your mousse on.
每次宴會結束  我總說"繞在手臂上卷好
After every fete, I say, "Wind it round your arm,
"別隨便揉成一團"
don't just put it away in a bunch."
"別把旗布團成團"
"Don't bunch the bunting!"
我今天要開始做軟糖了
I'm making a start on the fudge today
你要不要來幫忙
if you fancied lending a hand?
不行
I can't.
我得去巡邏
I've got to go on patrol.
我都不知道你又開始巡邏了
I didn't know you were back on patrol.
從今天十二點開始
Am from today, 12 o'clock.
你做決定永遠不跟人商量
All these decisions that you say nothing about.
巡邏又能怎么樣
How's going on patrol going to fix anything?
這對你的未來有幫助嗎
How's it looking after your future?
你什么都不告訴我  我要怎么幫你
And how can I help you if you won't talk to me?
媽  別擔心我
Mum, don't worry about me.
沒事的  我很好
It's OK, I'm fine.
我會好好的
I'll be fine.
"你還想要完整女友體驗套餐嗎"
'Are you wanting the full girlfriend experience again?
"還想嗎  想嗎"
'Again? Again?'
請進
Come in.
你來了
You're here!
我都要擔心了
I was getting worried.
不知道你會不會來
I wasn't sure you were coming.
把錢放在梳妝臺上吧
Leave the money on the dresser.
我不能久留
Em, look... Look, I can't stay long.
真可惜
Oh, shame.
這就要走啊  小吉  你才剛到家呢
You off out, Kier? You only just got here.
是啊  我得走了
Oh, yeah, I have to.
研討會都說什么了
Anything to report from t'workshop?
迪恩·霍爾頓在引領我們
Just Dean Halton's guide
轉變成社會文明人
to becoming a civilised member of society.
千里之行始于足下嘛
All have to start somewhere, I suppose.
我一直跟你說  爸
Yeah, I keep telling you, Dad,
沒有終又何來的始
it's not a start if it doesn't go anywhere.
我不過是日日去接受羞辱
It's just showing up for that day's humiliation.
職場就是這樣
That's the workplace for you.
你們三點會回來的吧
You'll be back by three, won't you?
會的
Course.
我可能回不來  媽
I don't think I can make it, Mum.
怎么了  你要去哪
Why, where you off to?
-艾米家  -說好來個家庭日的
- The bungalow. - Well, the plan was to have some family time,
全家人坐下來享受一頓周日午餐
all sit down together for Sunday lunch.
-那兩點三刻回來吧  -帶人一起來
- Back by quarter to, then, eh? - Bring someone.
帶誰
Who?
你的新朋友  也許那個
Well, one of your new friends. Maybe that...
艾米  那個獨特的女孩  我們非常歡迎
Amy, that nice unconventional girl. They'd be very welcome.
好吧  我問問
Yeah, I'll see.
不該是"家庭日"嗎
I thought it was going to be family time.
你看
Look.
沒填完整
They're not complete.
"復生時間"
"Time of Rising?"
他們不知道怎么辦
Well, what if they don't know?
那就讓他們搞清楚
Then they find out.
跟他們說  如果表格填得不對
Tell them if the forms aren't filled out correctly,
將被視為不合作
they'll be considered non-compliant.
瑪克辛·馬丁
菲利普·威爾森
看看你啊  衣冠筆挺帥氣逼人
Look at you, all done up and adorable!
艾米
Hi, Amy.
我復生那晚就是這樣
That's what happened the night I rose.
我記得的都已經說了
That's everything. That's all I remember.
你做禮拜遲到了
Oh, yeah, you're late for church.
謝謝  布萊恩  這感覺很棒  對吧
Thank you, Brian. It's a great feeling, isn't it?
知道為什么嗎
You know why?
活人想用羞恥感控制我們
Because the living have tried to control us with shame,
說出我們的復生故事
telling our Rising stories...
就是反抗的開始
is where we start to say no.
如果我們真要獲得自由
If we are serious about becoming free
首先要丟開的
the first shackle we have to throw off...
就是羞恥感
is shame.
大家都應該說出自己的復生故事
No Rising story should be left untold.
謝謝  布萊恩
Thank you, Brian.
你來了
You made it.
歡迎
Welcome.
你不是吧
Seriously?
菲利普·威爾森
大家盡快就坐  會議馬上開始了
If everyone'll take a seat as quick as you can, we'll get on.
第一項議程就是向你們介紹
Item number one on the agenda is to introduce you all
保護諾頓小分隊勇敢的成員們
to the brave men and women of the Roarton Protection Service.
正如你們所知  保諾隊的成立
As you know, the RPS has been set up
是為了應對近日發生的驚人事件
in response to the alarming events of recent days,
其中有些簡直讓人膽戰心驚
some of which, thinking about them'd make your blood run cold.
這位是隊長加里·肯德爾
There's Gary Kendal, he's the captain.
還有幾名
One or two other faces
也曾經是你們熟識的人類志愿軍成員
you'll know from Human Volunteer Force that was.
不就是一回事嗎
It's the same thing.
這是一個新隊伍
It's a new service.
他們的有些職責是相同的
It will be carrying out some of the same duties.
比如  在圍欄完工之前
For instance, until the perimeter fence is complete,
他們將在村子周邊的
there'll be regular patrols
樹林和田地例行巡邏
of the woods and fields around the village.
記住  我們大家是互相依靠的
And remember - they're relying on you as much as you are on them.
眼觀四路耳聽八方  有任何情況及時上報
So eyes and ears open, and anything you see, pass it on.
不死人不化妝  不戴隱形眼鏡就滿大街走
Undead walking around without make-up and lenses on.
別說了
Not now.
我在這里住了一輩子
Lived here all my life.
羅絲·歐頓  輪到你再發言
Rose Orton, you wait your turn.
-我可不想見到這種事  -是啊
- I don't want to be seeing that. - No!
召開此次會議的用意
The idea behind calling this meeting
就是讓大家說出心中的擔憂
was for people to air their concerns
作為一個社區  一起出謀獻策
and for us to decide together, as a community, what to do.
好了
Now...
誰想發言
who'd like to talk?
我們要拿僵尸妓院怎么辦
What are we going to do about t' rotter knocking shop?
阿比蓋爾·蘭博都告訴我了
Abigail Lamb told me all about it.
諾頓村還有這種事
This is going on in Roarton?
活人  和那種東西
The living...and those things?!
你怎么沒叫醒我
Why didn't you wake me?
不想叫醒你  你睡得很安穩
I didn't like to. You seemed so peaceful.
走吧
Go on.
惡心
Abomination!
居然跟僵尸通奸
Those giving themselves over to fornication
覬覦異族的肉體
and going after strange flesh!
我要說出去
I'll tell what you do.
我要告訴所有人
I'll tell everyone!
諾頓村怎么了
What happened to Roarton?
我們曾因堅持本真享譽國內
Did we stop being who we were,
如今卻變了樣子了嗎
what we were known for the country over?
我們變得和其他人一樣了嗎
Are we like everyone else now?
-她啥時成為我們一員了  -我們能忍受嗎
- When did she become "We"? - Do we tolerate this,
放任不管嗎
just put up with it?
我們曾經昂首挺胸  心存警惕
We used to be proud, vigilant!
我們曾是他人的楷模
We used to be an example to others.
我們就這么聽之任之嗎
Are we going to let this pass?
也許這就是我們需要的警鐘
Maybe this was the wake-up that we needed.
要我說就得盡快阻止此事
I think we put a stop to this as soon as we can.
我們組織起來  今晚把它搗毀
I think we get organised, we get down there tonight.
亨利  蘭思德  怎么  辦
What...about...Henry...Lonsdale?
亨利怎么辦
What about Henry?
三天了  我兒子一直沒回家
Three days since my son's been home.
蘭思德夫人  在場所有人都很理解你
Mrs Lonsdale, everyone here sympathises.
我沒跟你說話
I'm not talking to you.
從一開始  你就滿嘴謊言
Every word out of your mouth's been a lie from day one.
我跟你無話可說
I'm finished with you.
菲利普·威爾森說他會替我說話
Philip Wilson said he'd speak up for me.
既然他不在
Seeing as he's not here,
我就自己說個明白
I'll speak for myself to you,
你們是我的鄰居  我的朋友
my neighbours and my friends.
你們這么多人  有人找過他嗎
Out of the lot of you, who's tried to find him?
一個也沒有
Not one.
我已經解釋過  我們資源有限
I have explained that we cannot afford to devote our resources
不能浪費在尋找
to searching for someone
某個自愿失蹤的人上
who has gone missing of his own volition.
又來了  又在散播關于他的謊言
That's more of it! More lies spread against him.
要是你的孩子不知死活
What if it were your child you didn't know were alive or dead
你找人幫忙  卻無人理睬
and when you asked for help people just turn their backs,
甚至不問他情況  也不提起他的名字
don't even ask after him or mention his name,
好像他從不存在一樣  繼續干自己事
just carry on like he were never here?!
順便說一下  他們在列不合作者名單
By the way, they're making a list of noncompliants.
所以不參加回饋計劃
So not showing up to Give Back
這主意可能沒你想得那樣好
probably isn't the great idea you think it is,
還有派你的追隨者不化妝去參加
or sending your followers to it without cover-up on.
我的追隨者
My followers?
到處都是被洗腦的人
All these brainwashed people everywhere.
為什么
Why?
因為他們有信仰嗎
Because they have something to believe in?
對我來說吉倫  你才是被洗腦的
To me, Kieren, you're the one that's brainwashed,
-不過時間更長  -是嘛  別這樣
- just over a longer period. - Yeah, don't do that.
我怎么了
What am I doing?
無論你用什么方法說教  我不會聽的
Whatever conversion technique you're trying, I'm not up for it.
我沒打算把你怎樣
I'm not doing anything to you.
你知道我最煩什么嗎
Do you know what's so annoying?
你本可以做大事
Is that you could be great...
只要你能做兩秒鐘正常人
if you could just be a normal person for two seconds.
正常人做什么
What do normal people do?
我是認真的
I'm serious!
I'm serious.
告訴我你想要什么
Tell me what you want.
我會盡我所能  讓你如愿
I'll do anything I can to give it to you.
因為我心中一直堅定信仰
Because there's what I believe...
但現在又有了你
And then there's you.
好吧
Ok.
別
No.
你們兩個不許吵架
You two are not allowed to argue.
等我們仨成了鐵三角
You're going to feel so silly about this
你們就會覺得現在吵架可蠢了
when the three of us are best friends.
你們會說  "我們該聽艾米的
You're going to say, "Oh, we should have listened to Amy.
"艾米  那個天才小美女"
"Amy, the beautiful genius!"
你半小時前就裝滿了
You filled that half an hour ago.
-是嗎  -是的
- Did I? - Yeah.
那我把它放回去就好了
I'll just have to put it back out again.
我怎么了
What am I like?
不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no.
等等
Hang on.
她就在外邊
She's right out there.
那她就能知道了
I...I...Well, then she'll know.
聽著  如果我們要這么做
Look, if this is something we're doing,
我不希望她這么知道
I don't want her to find out like that.
我要親自告訴她
I want tell her.
好吧
Yeah.
好吧  好吧
Yeah. Yeah, fine.
盡快告訴她  好嗎
Just tell her soon, will you?
我非常抱歉
I am so sorry.
我有事耽擱了
I was held up.
你知道諾頓有個半死癥妓院嗎
Did you know there was a PDS brothel in Roarton?
不  不  我不知道
No. No, I didn't.
-真讓人擔心  -你該擔心的
- That's very concerning. - You would have...
要不是你錯過了一次重要的會議
if you hadn't missed a highly important meeting...
從頭至尾
entirely.
蘭博夫人有證據
Mrs Lamb has evidence.
所以它離關門不遠了
So there won't be one for long.
很好  我遲到的原因是..
Good. The reason that I was late...
這樣你就不必提亨利·蘭思德的事了
So you wouldn't have to bring up the Henry Lonsdale situation.
搞不懂你怎么會答應的
Why you would commit to that in the first place...
他媽媽來這了  大喊大叫一通
The mother turned up...here, shouting her head off.
這事失控了
It's getting out of hand.
她不肯接受現實
She won't accept the facts.
這件事會妨礙我們的目標
This whole thing is disrupting what we're trying to achieve.
你是她鄰居  對吧
You're her neighbour, right?
我在她隔壁長大
I grew up next door to her.
這樣  好吧
OK, then.
去找她
Go to her.
告訴她我給了你保密權限
Tell her I got you security clearance
你看過了情報
and that you've seen the intelligence,
有可靠的消息源確認看到亨利
a confirmed sighting of Henry in a training camp,
在一處集訓營中
from a reliable source.
什么消息源
What source?
你不明白
You don't understand.
我們正處于生死關頭
We're at a crucial point now.
處境危險  我們得保護好自己
There are real dangers and we need to protect ourselves.
我們在警醒群眾
We're galvanising now.
整頓妓院  管理不配合的半死癥患者
With this brothel thing and the steps against noncompliants,
亨利·蘭思德的事會讓大家分心的
Henry Lonsdale is a distraction.
這可不行
We cannot have that.
誰都不能分心
We cannot have distractions!
我們得做好準備
Things need to be ready.
消息來源是什么
What's the source?
這事得你去做  菲利普
I'm going to need you to do this, Philip.
如果沒有消息來源...
If there's no source...
我一直以為你想青云直上
My understanding was that you wanted to get ahead.
難道我記錯了嗎
Did I get that wrong?
-沒有  -那不就得了
- No. - Well, then.
只是...
It's just...
這樣做是不是太過分了
There are limits, aren't there?
讓你做的事很簡單
It's a simple instruction.
不如這樣  我給你點時間
I tell you what, why don't I give you some time
好好考慮下自己的未來
to think about your future?
我們會在妓院外面進行抗議示威
There's to be a protest outside the brothel.
你可以去之前先來這里見我
You can meet me here just beforehand.
這樣你大概還有...
That gives you about...
五個小時來想清楚自己要干什么
five hours to decide what it is you think you're doing.
這才像你
There she is.
目空一切的冷面美女殺手
Stone-cold, shit-kicking, badass fox.
閉嘴吧你
Shut up.
不好意思  你可不能這么和上級說話
Excuse me. You can't talk like that to your commanding officer.
-你忘了嗎  -我又沒說要加入你的隊伍
- Forgot about that, didn't you? - Never said I was joining up.
加入了  我就每天都能看你穿這身了
But if you were to, I'd get to see you in this every day.
迪恩回來了也不錯
I mean, it's good to have Dean back and everything.
不是說這小伙不性感  但是...
I'm not saying he's not a sexy bloke but...
畢竟跟你不一樣
it's not quite the same thing, is it?
這么看你不得不加入了
So it looks like we have no choice in the matter.
沒得選了
It's out of our hands.
他說我像自由的化身
He said I looked like freedom.
你不覺得那是個比喻嗎
You don't think that might have been more a metaphor?
我不是比喻  布萊恩  他盯著我說的
I'm not a metaphor, Brian. He was looking right at me.
西蒙期望我有所動作
Simon expects...
-你打算干什么  -我...
- What are you going to do? - I'm...
我告訴你什么打算
I tell you what I'm going to do.
我打算讓西蒙以我為傲
I'm going to make Simon proud.
你聯系我們是正確的  蘭博太太
You did the right thing getting in touch, Mrs Lamb.
我們會仔細梳理錄像帶
The tapes will take some sifting.
村里有些人可要傻眼了
There are some people in this village in for a nasty shock.
我相信您的證據會引起軒然大波的
I'm sure that evidence of yours will have a very deep impact.
我下午開車過來取錄像帶
I'll be around this afternoon with a car to pick it up.
你能行吧
You going to be OK with this?
不過是巡邏罷了
It's a patrol.
你確定
Are you sure?
我們可以繞過亨利...
Cos we don't have to go anywhere near where Henry...
事發的地方
where it happened.
好吧
Right, good.
我們走快點  半小時就能結束了
I reckon if we move fast, we're out of here in half an hour.
我們分頭走  15分鐘就完事了
15 minutes if we split up.
你巡那邊  我負責這邊
You take that way, I'll take this.
差十分的時候回這里見
Meet back here at ten to.
好啊  聽你的
All right. Whatever you say.
我就說你有種
Told you you're badass.
加里
Gary?
誰啊
Who's that?
等等
Hey, wait.
別走了
Stop.
沒事了  沒事了
It's OK. It's OK.
你沒事了
You're OK.
流鼻血  注射后戰栗
So, nosebleeds, tremor following administration.
還有別的癥狀嗎
Any other symptoms at all?
今早我打算做早飯來著
This morning I tried to make myself breakfast.
我們不吃飯  我都忘了
We don't eat. I'd forgotten.
我總是忘事
I'm forgetting a lot.
謝謝你能在這里見我
Thanks for seeing me here.
我不想去見羅素醫生  他太奇怪了
Didn't want to go back to Dr Russo because he's weird.
我覺得他就是有點羞澀
Oh, I think it's mainly shyness.
我不想讓我周圍的人擔心我
I didn't want the people I live with to worry
覺得我哪里不正常
and think that something's wrong...
萬一真的有問題
if something IS wrong.
我在手冊里沒找到
I'm not seeing any mention
有關你的癥狀或是副作用的描述
of your particular combination of symptoms or side effects,
不管是哪樣  我們可以變通下你的藥
whichever they are. What we might do is tweak your medication.
有時也管用的
Sometimes that works.
找到了  這個
Now, here we go. Look.
"哈普倫和韋斯頓宣布
"Halperin & Weston
"新一代半死癥治療藥物
"announce positive results in clinical trials
"的臨床試驗結果積極有效
"for next-generation PDS treatments.
"使用升級版神經替林的實驗對象
"Subjects taking Neurotriptyline Plus
"與服用無效對照劑的對象相比
"reported decreased incidence of anxiety or nervousness,
"睡眠時間增加
"lengthened sleep durations
"焦慮緊張現象有所減輕"
"and less interpersonal distress compared to placebo."
他們還挺勤奮
They've been busy!
"有效成分有神經替林乳糖..."
"Active ingredients are Neurotriptyline lactose..."
我看其實差不多
It's more of the same, if I'm honest.
試試吧
Give it a go.
給  看看換這個管用不
There you go. See if that does the trick.
升級版神經替林
不管用再來  好嗎
If not, pop back again, OK?
靠  該死
Shit! Bloody shit!
-菲利普  -怎么
- Philip! - Yes?
-這位是...  -已經認識了
- This is... - Already acquainted.
抱歉
Sorry.
沒事  時不時的該教訓教訓它們
No. Good to show 'em who's boss every now and then.
我原來有個附帶時鐘的收音機
I had a clock-radio once.
我就沒怎么管
I let it get out of line.
都賴我
It's my own fault, really.
我經常大段時間不理它...
I'd leave it alone for long periods...
白天的時候
during the day.
好了
Right, then.
你沒事吧
You OK?
稍等
Just give me a second.
你不用這樣  不行就算了
You don't have to do this. We can forget all about it.
不  你說你想讓我了解你的世界  所以
No, you said you wanted me to see your world, so...
我沒想讓你堅守什么承諾
I'm not holding you to anything.
我說到就要做到  同時也能
I said I'd do it. I'll do it. It's part of the...
更加了解你
getting to know you.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
附近有人嗎
Is anyone around?
沒有
No.
千萬別有人
There'd better not be.
我知道  走吧
Yeah, yeah. Start walking.
-我看起來怎么樣  -太難看了
- How do I look? - So bad.
謝謝
Thank you.
沒事
It's OK.
他直直地看著我  像是在問我為什么
He was looking right at me. It's like he was asking me why.
小潔  小點聲
Jem, keep it down.
我覺得他們在追殺我  所有僵尸
I thought they were after me. All of them.
我們殺掉的每一個
Everyone we ever did.
還想再來一杯嗎
Do you want another?
好
Yeah.
請再來一樣的  珀莉
Same again, please, Pearl.
這兩杯我請  珀莉
Those are on me, Pearl.
你真是太好了
That's very kind of you.
還你們人情  朋友
Debt of gratitude, mate.
知道你們在巡邏  就感覺安全多了
Feel safer already, knowing you lot are out there.
我是覺得
As far as I'm concerned,
不該再讓你們出錢了
that hand doesn't go in your pocket.
別誤會  酒吧沒這條規矩
So as you know, that's not a house policy.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers, then. - Cheers.
好人
Good man.
我一直在做惡夢
I keep having bad dreams.
每個夢里都有亨利
Henry is in them an' all.
小潔  聽著
Jem, look.
亨利已經死了
Henry's gone.
你得活在當下
You just need to be in the here and now.
該死的  誰沒干過虧心事
I mean, fuck's sake, we've all done stuff.
但總放不下只會讓我們變得軟弱
But dwelling on it is only going to weaken us.
聽著  現在我們都活著并且在一起
So, listen. Here and now we're together and we're alive,
對我來說已經很滿足了
and that's two boxes ticked for me already.
看來馬上又要有免費暢飲了
Looks like there's a free piss-up in the offing as well.
趕快把這杯喝完然后裝作很渴的樣子
So knock that one back quick and look thirsty.
真不敢相信沒錄上
Can't believe it didn't record.
你真是大救星蘭博夫人  我都要絕望了
You're a life-saver, Mrs Lamb. Bereft I was.
我一看完就立刻還給你
I'll get this back to you as soon as I've watched it.
再見
Bye, now.
蘭博夫人
Mrs Lamb?
別  我想跟你說幾句話
No, I was wondering if you and I could have a quick word.
求你了
Please.
我懇求你
Look, I implore you.
說吧
Well?
有些事應該讓你知道
There's something you need to know.
現在回去還不晚
It's not too late to back out.
你能別再說這種話了嗎
Can you stop saying that?
拜托  我很好  我非常放松
Please. I'm fine. I'm completely relaxed.
-那是你爸爸嗎  -糟糕
- Is that your dad? - Shit.
說你喜歡他的牛仔褲
Say you like his jeans.
什么
What?
-好吧  -爸爸
- All right. - Hey, Dad.
西蒙  這是我爸爸  史蒂夫
Simon, this is my dad, Steve.
你好  史蒂夫
Hi, Steve.
牛仔褲不錯
Like your jeans.
謝謝
Thanks very much.
蘇  吉倫帶了個朋友回來  西蒙
Sue, Kieren's brought a mate back. Simon.
太好了
Very nice.
你好  蘇
Hello, Sue.
謝謝你們招待我
Thanks for having me.
很高興你來我們家
Lovely to have you here.
希望午飯能讓你喜歡  西蒙
Well, I hope you like lunch, Simon.
當然
Er...sure. Er...
在他不吃的飯里  這次肯定排前三
It's definitely in his top three meals we don't eat.
你很樂意維持這個裁決  是吧
You're happy to stick with that finding, are you?
你這是什么意思  警督
What are you implying, Detective Inspector?
給馬丁女士的留言
帕特里克·休斯
維生黨
回電  緊急
馬丁女士  我太不應該了  是吧
Ms Martin! I'm terrible, aren't I?
這個點看電視劇
This time of day.
我還以為我是諾頓數我最迷《苦斗》
I thought I was Roarton's biggest Hard Graft fan.
阿比蓋爾·蘭博錄了全集
Abigail Lamb records them all.
你看到留言了吧
You've got the message, then?
帕特里克·休斯  維生黨總部
Patrick Hughes. Victus central office.
是一個說話非常粗魯的男人
A man with a very brusque tone, I must say.
如果這位朋友堅持說他在清潔槍時
I can understand our friend here sustaining
意外射傷了自己一次  我還可以理解
one accidental bullet wound while cleaning his gun,
但兩次
but two...
不
Oh, no!
開什么玩笑
You've got to be joking.
這是什么
What is this?
這帶子你從哪拿到的
Where did you get this tape?
你應當引以為傲
You should be very proud.
你養大了一個如此好如此虔誠的年輕人
That's a fine, religious young man you've raised.
花了那么多時間去做拓展活動
Giving all that time to his outreach work.
還有那么多私下的善舉
All his good deeds in secret, too.
試著說服女人們脫離罪惡
Trying to convince women to turn away from sin.
他都跟我說了  你知道嗎
He told me all about it. Do you know,
要不是他得來找我
I don't think he would've said a word
找我要那些帶子的話
if he hadn't had to come
我想他還會絕口不提的
and ask me for those tapes.
當然了  我們不應該
Still, we couldn't have people
讓人誤會他  是吧
thinking the wrong thing, could we?
來吧
Come on.
西蒙一定會愛死這個的
Simon is going to love this.
他知道了一定會大吃一驚
He is going to freak when he finds out.
驚喜嗎
In a good way?
你以為要怎么吹響自由的號角  布萊恩
What do you think a blow for freedom is, Brian?
你們好
Hey, there.
把鎖撬了
Get the lock off.
我們是朋友  我們和你們一樣
We're friends. We're like you.
快點  佐伊
Quick as you can, then, Zoe.
你們自由了  是的  自由
You're free. Yes, freedom.
他們隨時可能發起攻擊的
Probably make a move sometime around now.
你嚇著他們了
You're scaring them.
-快走吧  -佐伊  說真的
- Come, please. - Zoe, seriously.
慢點  布萊恩  你看起來太外行
Slow down, Brian. You look like an amateur.
廉價的報警系統
Cut-price alarm system!
我的周日下午就這么泡湯了
My Sunday afternoon up in smoke.
不
Oh, no.
很不錯  謝謝
This is nice. Thank you.
我就說沒人會拒絕好吃的牛肉的
I always say you can't beat a good bit of beef.
你的那個老妹說她三點回來
That sister of yours said she'd be here by three.
也就是說  按照她一貫的表現
Which, if previous experience is anything to go by,
從現在到午夜都有沒準
means any time between now and midnight.
就別等她等到菜都涼了
No point in letting it go cold.
話說  史蒂夫  你和蘇是怎么認識的
So, Steve, how did you and Sue meet?
工作認識的
Work.
工作
那你們倆呢
What about the two of you?
一樣  工作認識的
The same. Work.
我很欣賞他愿意回饋
I like the way he gave back.
-你讓我感覺很棒  -是嗎  你也是
- You make me feel good. - Do I? Back at yer.
好吧  爸爸
All right, Dad.
加里來吃午飯
Gary's come for lunch.
不打擾你們就行  史蒂夫
If that's OK with you, Steve.
沒問題  挺好的  吉倫帶朋友來了
No problem at all. Very nice. Kieren's brought his mate back.
小潔  吃飯前不想換身衣服嗎
Jem, do you want to change at all before eating?
算了吧  我餓死了
Not really. I'm starving.
也好  先吃飯
Getting stuck in is probably the best plan.
謝謝  史蒂夫
Cheers, Steve.
我們剛好喝過幾杯了
We've had a few pints, as it happens.
這是吉倫的朋友西蒙
This is Kieren's mate Simon.
這是小潔  和加里
Jem. And Gary.
很高興
All right.
人都齊了  越多越歡樂
There we are. More, the merrier.
沒錯  菜夠吃
Yeah, plenty to go around.
是啊  反正有倆人也不吃
Yeah, well, there would be, wouldn't there?
大家在這里就冷靜點  行嗎
Shall we keep it cool, guys, while we're here?
我沒問題  伙計
No problem this end, pal.
哦  皮真厚
Oi. Cheeky sod.
媽  那些彩旗的結都解開了嗎
Did you manage to get all the knots out of the bunting, Mum?
都解開了
Finally.
一直在忙吧  蘇
They keeping you busy, Sue?
蘇在村民游樂會策劃組里
Sue's on the planning committee for the village fete.
應該很忙吧
It's all go, in't it?
-事確實多  -瑪克辛·馬丁也不幫忙
- Oh, yeah, plenty to do. - Not helped by a certain Maxine Martin.
瑪克辛怎么了
What's Maxine done?
她覺得游樂會
She thinks the fete should
應該有個紀念復生的展臺
have a stand to commemorate the Rising.
好像她們還不夠忙似的
As if they haven't got enough to worry about.
那有什么問題  蘇
Well, what's the problem there, Sue?
大部分時候我們都盡量避免分裂
Well, most years we try to avoid anything divisive.
確實值得紀念  不是嗎
It's worth commemorating, though, in't it?
值得小小回顧一下
Worth a little backwards glance.
犧牲的那些人  他們的英勇事跡
People making the ultimate sacrifice, acts of valour and that,
小潔也在其中
Jems here, included.
光她的英勇事跡就夠好多展臺的了
They should have umpteen stands, all Jem's heroic deeds.
大部分都是樂隊
Well, it's mostly jams.
基德森那次就該好好紀念下
Have one for that time in the Kitsons' place.
你還記得嗎  我們在基德森
Do you remember that? We were at Kitsons'.
那里沒什么好看的  我尿急
There was nothing much to show up there. I'm caught short,
就跑上樓上廁所
so I nip upstairs to use the loo,
沒帶武器  大錯特錯了
leaving my weapon, right? Big mistake.
我還大聲跟你說來著  是吧
And I shout down to you, don't I?
"下水道堵了  味道太難聞了"
"Summat's up wi' drains." Cos the smell's that bad.
餐桌上談廁所不大合適吧
Don't know how much toilet talk we want at the dinner table.
我環顧四周  看到一個
I look round and there's this
超級大僵尸朝我沖過來
massive big bloody rabid just coming right at me.
死前肯定是混混
Must have been, what, 18st of him.
在浴缸里打盹來著
Been having a nap in t'bath.
廚藝超水平發揮啊  蘇
You've outdone yourself here, Sue.
怪不得有味道  但我回到角落
It explains the smell anyway. But I'm backing into a corner.
還有誰覺得媽媽廚藝很棒的
Who else thinks Mum's outdone herself?
我爬上抽水馬桶
I'm climbing up on t'toilet bowl with
手里只拿著電動牙刷自衛
nothing but an electric toothbrush to defend myself with
然后又出現了兩個僵尸
when two more of them turn up.
她出現了  手里拿著柯式槍  開槍
This one shows up, Colt in hand... Boom!
打死了第一個  腦子濺了一地
Pops the first one there. Brains across the tiles.
奶油韭菜還可以嗎
Everyone OK for creamed leeks?
第二個也掉腦袋了
Second one, top of neck.
那個肥僵尸還朝著我來  是吧
Fat lad's still coming at me, in't he?
我手上只有牙刷  她走過去...
Me wi' me trusty toothbrush. She walks up to it...
開槍  槍堵住了
Click. Gun jams.
我就說  行了  晚安  西貢
I'm like, "All right, OK, good night, Saigon!"
她非常冷靜  扯下浴簾桿
Cool as you like, she rips down t'shower pole...
一桿戳下  直穿眼窩
Boom! Straight through t'eye hole.
但沒完  沒完  還沒完呢...
But wait, no, no, no, no. That's not it. This...
這個狂暴僵尸  半死癥患者
This rabid, this PDS sufferer,
就變成這樣
starts going over like this.
但浴簾桿還插在他腦袋里
"Argh!" Only t'pole's still stuck in its head.
一低頭剛好打到我
Hits me on t'way down.
我失去平衡  雙腳都踩馬桶里了
I lose my balance, don't I? Both feet end up in t'toilet bowl.
鞋濕了  襪子濕了
Boots wet, socks wet.
這就是你在戰爭中的作為嗎
That what you did in the war, is it?
殺人
Kill people?
-算了吧  -不  不行
- Leave it. - No, no, I won't.
我也殺過人
I killed people, too.
我自己其實也有個有趣的故事
I've a funny story of my own, actually.
我從死復生
I rose from the dead.
-在那之后  我開人們的腦子  -吉倫...
- And, then, after that I ripped people apart. - Kieren...
也許不是很有趣  但你還是可以
OK, maybe it's not that funny but you can
坐著聽聽  就像我們聽你的故事一樣
sit there and listen to it anyway, like we did with you.
-吉倫  別  -不  你說得沒錯  伙計
- Kieren, don't. - Nah, you're all right, mate.
仔細聽我的故事
Listen to the story!
很奇怪  因為剛開始只有黑暗
It's weird. First because all there is is just darkness.
一片漆黑
It's so dark.
睜不睜眼都沒區別
Doesn't make a difference if your eyes are open or closed.
你都覺得自己是被活埋了
What you think is that you've been buried alive.
吉倫  拜托
Kieren, please.
這可不好玩
Not ideal.
那種完全的...恐慌  懂嗎
That's proper...proper panic, that. You know.
你猛擊棺材蓋
You hit out at the lid of the coffin
雖然你知道打不開
even though you know there's no way.
但過會棺材蓋松動了
But then it starts to give.
你得一路撥開土壤  挖出道路
You have to push your way through all the soil.
要挖個沒完  是吧  好長時間
Takes ages, doesn't it? Takes so long.
吉倫...
Kieren...
但突然...
But then suddenly...
感覺變了
...something's different.
你指尖有風吹拂
You feel the wind on the tips of your fingers,
還有雨
and the rain.
因為那之前還不確定自己在哪里
Because before that you're not really sure where you are but...
不過現在就知道了  你繼續往外爬
but now you know. And you're pushing through
然后什么都感覺到了  月光
and then all this stuff at once. The moon...
還有狂風暴雨
and this incredible storm blowing.
午夜的鐘聲響起  你就站在那里
And the clock chiming midnight and you're just standing there.
周圍空無一人
Nobody else around.
感知著四面八方
And all of it pushing into me.
空無一人  你確定嗎
No-one else. Are you sure?
不確定  你知道我什么感覺嗎
No. But you know what I felt?
有別的墓穴打開了嗎
Were any other graves open?
其他墓穴都好好的  別打斷我好嗎
No, the other graves are fine. I'm trying to say something.
那種感覺
That feeling...
就像是初生一樣
it's like what being born must be like,
但這次你了解來龍去脈
except you've got context.
說實話  死亡
Because, honestly, dead...
到那時為止  只有恐懼  別無其他
everything... up until then was fear. Everything.
活著也不過是面臨不同層次的恐懼
Even when I was alive, just different levels of fear.
接著那感覺就消失了
And then it's gone.
你只想著"來啊  喂飽我啊"
And you're like, "Yeah, come on, give it to me, fill me up!"
知道嗎  加里
And you know what, Gary?
那種饑渴  純粹的食欲
This hunger, this appetite,
讓我忍不住大快朵頤
I could not wait to get started.
夠了
That's enough!
聽到了嗎  我不想聽了
Do you hear me? I will not have it.
-我過分了嗎  爸  -吉倫  別這樣
- Did I cross the line, Dad? - Kieren, please.
他們就能坐在那里擊掌歡慶
While they sit around and high-five each other
屠殺我們的事  跟講笑話似的
about killing us, like it's a big joke!
大家就都不介意
Oh, no, that's fine with everyone!
我就講個故事都不行  很抱歉
I say one thing and that is indecent?! I'm sorry,
但這也太不講理了
but that is bullshit!
走吧  西蒙
Come on, Simon.
-快走  -好
- Come on! - Yeah.
你知道我為你驕傲對吧  菲利普
You do know I'm proud of you, Philip?
西維婭和亨利的事你會正確抉擇的對吧
You'll do what's right by Sylvia and Henry, won't you?
我會的
Yes, I will.
馬丁女士  我決定不要...
Miss Martin? I've decided I'm not going...
桑德拉·福尼斯的朋友給了她這卷錄像帶
Sandra Furness got this tapefrom a friend of hers,
一個叫阿比蓋爾·蘭博的女人
a woman called Abigail Lamb.
蘭博夫人最近的錄像帶有點多
Mrs Lamb's had a bit of a run on video tapes recently.
苦斗7
所以她才忘了這盤上的內容
I expect that's why she forgot what was on this one.
意外射傷了自己一次
Sustaining one accidental bullet wound
我還可以理解  不過兩次
'while cleaning his gun, but two...'
現在一切都好說了  是不是  菲利普
Suddenly everything has become very simple, hasn't it, Philip?
你一直在說謊
You tell lies all the time.
現在無非是需要你再說一個而已
All you need to do now is just tell one more.
完事了你可以來參加抗議
And afterwards you can come to the protest,
想說兩句也行
maybe even say a few words.
然后重新戴上你的偽裝
And go back to being the person you say you are.
蘭思德夫人住哪不用我告訴你吧
You know where Mrs Lonsdale lives.
你該去了
Time you got on with it.
說不定又是你哥哥
It's probably your brother...
想起什么笑話要講
with another one of his funny stories.
走吧  參加妓院抗議
Come on. Brothel protest.
今天不該我們當班
We're not on tonight.
又不需要很多警衛
It's not goingto take more than one or two on security.
我已經跟瑪克辛說了
I already spoke to Maxine.
-她現在要所有人都去  -為什么
- Yeah, well, now she wants everyone there. - Why?
以防妓女襲擊她唄  我怎么知道  快走
In case tarts attack? I don't know. Come on.
紀        念
多蘿西·溫蒂·戴爾
-可憐人  -不知羞恥
- Your poor mam! - No shame!
我們是來表明態度的
Right, we're here to give out a signal.
趕緊完事  別節外生枝
Let's get the job done. And we don't engage.
我們不是來閑聊的
We're not here for conversation.
你和克雷格抄后門
You and Craig go round the back,
我  山姆和安迪走前門
me, Sam and Andy'll go in the front.
-好的  伙計  -讓我們去抓僵尸吧
- All right, mate. - Let's bag some rotters.
菲利普
Philip...
-抱歉深夜來訪  -進來吧  菲利普
- Sorry to call so... - Come in, Philip.
他們要的和平共處就是這樣嗎
Is this what they meant when they told us to integrate?
不能容忍
Of course not!
我只能說  感謝上帝我們終于清醒了
Thank God we're waking up, is all I can say,
因為這才是個開始
because this is only a start.
只要這毒瘤還未根除
As long as this illness goes untreated,
我們就處于危險之中
we are vulnerable!
反對半死癥妓院
在這等著  我去看看怎么回事
Wait here. I'll go and find out what's happening.
你  進去
You, in.
進去
Get in there.
站起來  快點
Get up now. Get up now.
讓他們別動
Keep them here.
快走
Come on.
走  小潔  快點
Come on, Jem, shake a leg.
我們在干嘛
What are we doing?
做正確的事  大家都希望的事
The right thing, what everyone wants.
你都聽到了  大家又開始依賴我們了
You heard 'em down pub. Folks are counting on us again.
請聽我說  你們不明白
Listen, please. You don't understand.
我現在出去  就會失去一切
If I go out there, I'll lose everything!
那就對了  朋友  和其他人放一起
Not confused by that at all, friend. Put him with the rest.
我已經在收拾了
I'm going.
那就再快點
Let's see if we can hurry things along, then, shall we?
快走  小潔
Come on, Jem.
我們接到了新消息
We've had some more information.
-有一個  -稍等  打斷一下
- There... - Just... before...
先坐下再說吧
Please sit down. Come on.
我想阻止她的  菲利普
I tried to stop her, Philip,
但是  她的謊言在我頭腦里生根發芽
but she's... she's put these lies in my head that...
讓我覺得亨利還活著
Henry's maybe still out there.
這不是希望  這感覺才是最糟的
It's not hope, it's the worst feeling.
這只是拖延
It's dragging it out.
我明知道她在說謊
I know they're lies,
但我憑一己之力卻無法阻止
but I can't let them go on my own,
知道也沒用
even though I know.
我真的知道
I know.
你一直都是個嚴肅的孩子
You've always been such a serious boy.
哪怕你小時候在玩
I'd see you playing out, even as a toddler.
眉頭都皺那么緊
Big frown on your face,
像有什么惹得你很生氣
like something had just made you very angry.
但從來沒見你發過飆
Never saw you lash out, though.
也沒見你干過殘忍的事
Never saw you do the cruel things,
所以我知道你是個好孩子
so I know you're a good boy.
我只想聽些真話  菲利普
All I need is some truth, Philip.
拜托
Please.
行了
Right, then.
把他們帶出去
Let's have 'em.
惡心  畜生
Disgusting! Swine!
僵尸站這邊  嫖客站這邊
Rotters this side, prozzies this side.
乖乖排好隊
Nice, neat rows.
頭抬起來  給大伙瞧瞧
Let everyone see your faces.
請大家安靜一下
Can I have your attention, please?
拜托  大家安靜一下
Please, can I have your attention?
謝謝
Thank you.
我覺得不能再繼續下去了
I think we should stop this.
不能繼續什么
Stop it?
大伙不能再繼續自我欺騙了
I think we should all stop pretending.
自我欺騙
Pretending?
只騙得了自己一時而已
You can only pretend for so long,
之后還得面對真實的自我
and then you're back stuck with yourself.
-你什么意思  -我的意思是
- About what? - What I'm trying to explain is that...
覺得自己純潔無暇的想法
if the idea that you were ever a pure person,
只會讓事情變本加厲
it just makes everything else so much worse.
讓人對你們失望
It makes you so disappointing.
沒有人是純潔的
People aren't pure.
我們跟他們一樣的  有人性好壞
We are not good any more than they're evil or they're inhuman.
或許我們把他們想的丑惡不堪
Maybe we only have to pretend they're bad
只為了粉飾自己有多好
because we have to pretend we're good.
如果我們能接受真實的自己
But if we could just accept our real selves
擁抱真實的自己  愛自己
and live with who we really are and love ourselves,
也許就可能
then maybe...
也許就能接受彼此  和平共處
maybe we could accept and live with and...
還有相愛
and love.
當我沒說
Forget it.
你站在那里干什么
Hey, what are you doing over there?
他跟這幫僵尸們是一路的
He's been at it with rotters!
快走  滾出去
No, go on, get out!
幾位  笑一笑
Big smiles, everyone.
惡心
Disgusting.
是誰  誰在那
Who's there? Who is it?
一個僵尸
A zombie!
比一個僵尸還可怕
Worse than a zombie!
什么會比一個僵尸還可怕
What's worse than a zombie?
兩個嗎
Two?
一個喝醉的僵尸
A drunk zombie.
對于你性生活被曝光的事情
Terrible news about the full disclosure
我表示痛心  順便說一句
of your sex life, by the way.
你跟他們站在一起  不明智啊
Not going down brilliantly with the townsfolk.
現在你名聲掃地  又是戀尸癖
Your reputation's in tatters, what with...necrophilia
又是喜歡僵尸什么的
and fancying rotters.
不是好孩子干的事
Nice boys don't do that!
不用了  謝謝你
No, thank you.
我可清楚你嘴都舔過哪里
I know where that mouth's been.
你怎么可能會喝醉
How can you be drunk?
自我暗示
Power of suggestion?
感官記憶
Sense memory?
我不是真的醉了
And I'm not really.
建議你做好準備
I'd say prepare yourself
被處私刑  或者慘遭社會排斥
for some sort of lynching or social ostracism.
你在跟我談排斥嗎
You're talking to me.
我還是相當友好的
I'm very nice, though.
而且我現在特別能忍白癡
I also have a high tolerance for idiots just now,
尤其是失望的白癡
especially disappointed idiots.
我不是癡迷于半死癥患者
I don't fancy people with PDS...
-這一類  -我懂  只迷性工作者嘛
- as such. - Right, just the sex workers.
我只是找其中的一位
I went to one sex worker.
一位  哪一位啊
One! What's one
因為她會讓我想到某個人
Because she reminded me of someone.
誰關心啊
Who's counting?
因為  我確實喜歡半死癥患者
Because I do like some people with PDS.
很少的幾個
Very few.
其實  只有你
You...in fact.
*所以這里  就是你想來的地方*
*So this is where you wanted to be*
*真是萬分遺憾  你不在我身邊*
*It's a goddamn shame that you're not here with me*
別擔心  不用多久了
Don't worry. Not long now.
*再無法見到你的容顏*
*And I can't see yourface any more*
*若是可以  一切不會再像昨天*
*If I could it wouldn't look like before*
*看似好像*
*Look like*
我也醒著  所以不要想著
I'm awake, too, so it's no good
把自己這只手臂咬下來
thinking about gnawing your own arm off.
我想或者留給你算了  考慮到
I thought maybe I could leave that to you, given...
我不知道你居然會開玩笑
I didn't know you made jokes.
我沒開玩笑
I don't.
我找到了第一個復生者
I've found the First Risen.
你該見見他
You should see him.
他太美了
He's beautiful.
*該死  我愛著*
*Damn, I love...*
乖乖認罪 可以判你緩期執行
Admit your guilt and we'll hand you a suspended sentence.
筆    供
不是我干的  爸爸
I didn't do it, Dad.
他們威脅說要把他送回諾福克
They've threatened to send him back to Norfolk.
不是我干的
I didn't do it!
*該死  我愛著*
*Damn, I love...*
這個有解藥
There's a cure?
你肯幫忙的話  就有可能
With your help, there could be.
這些真的有必要嗎  約翰
Is all this necessary, John?
我對她做了什么
What did I do to her?!
他沒有變僵尸  他的情況不樂觀
He's not turning rabid. He's had some bad news.
*該死  我愛著*
*Damn, I love... *
我不想做僵尸  根本沒有生活可言
I don't want to live as a rabid. It's no kind of life.
沒事的  沒事的
You're fine, you're fine, you're fine, you're fine.
*該死  我愛著*
*Damn, I love...*
西蒙  我的孩子
Simon, my son,
我的第十二位門徒
my 12th disciple.
我選擇你來改變歷史
I've chosen you to change history.
*該死 我愛著*
*Damn, I love...*
*該死  我愛著你*
*Damn, I love...you*